Slim Ouertani June-81, Tunisian

ouertani@gmail.com • (00966)-(0)-583012381 • Riyadh (Saudi Arabia) linkedin.com/in/ouertani • ouertani.github.io • jroller.com/ouertani • twitter.com/ouertani

Architect, InfoQ Fr Editor, Cloud & SOA Trainer Togaf, Archimate, PMP, SOA, Cloud, Spring, Java, Cmmi, ITIL, Mongo, Scala

Summary

Slim Ouertani is solution architect, InfoQ-Fr editor, Cloud and SOA trainer, founder and organizer of Riyadh IT Architecture Meetup. After his bachelor's degree in computer science, Slim spent over than 10 years in multinational companies such as Orange, Sagem and STMicroelectronics as architect, international agile coach and Head of IT development department. His main role was to build, design and collaborate in the development of enterprise solutions.

Slim regularly contributes to InfoQ-FR community where he is the author of many articles and news. you to follow him on twitter @ouertani.

He's broad certified as in addition to his SOA and Cloud certifications: Trainer & Architect, Slim holds multiple certifications including Togaf 9, Archimate 2, PMP, ITIL, CMMi, Mongo, Spring, JAVA, SCALA and reactive pro-

Trained as an architect, Slim specializes in enterprise Java development, functional programming focusing on highly scalable applications and now expanding his experience to cloud computing.

Slim enjoys open source contribution and invite

Experience

Al-Elm Information Security Solution Architect	Riyadh, SAUDI ARABIA 06-2014 – present
Sofrecom (Orange FT Group) Software Architect, International Agile Coach	Tunis, Tunisia 03-2013 – 06-2014
Zenika JEE Architect	Paris, FRANCE 12-2012 – 03-2013
Orange Head of Development and Tools Manager	Tunis, Tunisia 01-2010 – 11-2012
Sagem Software & Technologies Solution Architect	Tunis, Tunisia 06-2009 – 01-2010
STMicroelectronics Coordinator	Tunis, Tunisia 02-2006 – 12-2007
GL TRADE Developer & designer	Tunis, Tunisia 08-2005 – 12-2005

Please refer to my Linked-in profile for a more complete list of work experiences along with recommendations.

Certificate

Archimate Certified, Open Group	Score 82%, 02-2016
Archimate Foundation, Open Group	Score 97%, 02-2016
Cloud Trainer, Arcitura	10-2015
Cloud Architect, Arcitura	With Honors, 10-2015
Cloud Professional, Arcitura	With Honors, 09-2015
Togaf Certified, Open Group	Score 90%, 06-2015
ITIL Foundation, Exin	Score 95%, 06-2015
Togaf Foundation, Open Group	Score 95%, 04-2015
Project Management Professional, PMI	03-2015
SOA Trainer, Arcitura	01-2015
SOA Architect, Arcitura	With Honors, 12-2014
SOA Professional, Arcitura	With Honors, 11-2014

Introduction to Cmmi for development, Cmmi Institute	09-2014
Entrepreneurship for all, EFFECTUATION, EMLYON	Score 75,8%, 01-2014
Principles of Reactive Programming, Coursera	Score 97.5%, 01-2014
MongoDB for DBAs, MongoDB	Score 94%, 11-2013
MongoDb for java, MongoDb	Score 95%, 10-2013
Spring Framework 3, Pivotal	Score 94%, 02-2013
Java 6 Programmer Certified Professional, Oracle	Score 100%, 08-2012
Team Performance, STMicroelectronics	04-2007
English, British Council	4B, 02-2007
GL Certified Professional, GL TRADE	09-2005

Education

National School of Computer ScienceENSI Graduation Project in Computer Engineering	Tunis,Tunisia 2005
National School of Computer ScienceENSI Bachelor Degree in Computer Science	Tunis, Tunisia 2002 – 2005
Tunis Preparatory Institute for Engineering StudiesIPEIT Preparatory Courses (Math Sup, Math Spe)	Tunis, Tunisia 2000 – 2002
Hannibal (Pre-university Secondary Education)	Ariana, Tunisia 1994 – 2000

Other Activities

InfoQ Fr Editor

http://www.infoq.com/fr/author/Slim-Ouertani

BLOGGGING

http://java.dzone.com/users/slim.ouertani http://ouertani.github.io http://www.jroller.com/ouertani http://twitter.com/ouertani

MAGAZINE

From Microservices to SOA - 20.07.2015 Service Technology Magazine - Issue XCI http://servicetechmag.com/I91/0715-1

OPEN SOURCE

https://github.com/ouertani http://www.reactive-streams.org

Founder & Organizer

Riyadh IT Architecture Meetup http://www.meetup.com/Riyadh-IT-Architecture

INTERVIEW

Paremus, SCA with OSGI, David Savage http://www.prosyst.com/07.02.2009 http://goo.gl/H5yJzY

STAMPLE

https://stample.co Scala, Akka, Play ElasticSearch, MongoDb, Amazon S3, GreenCloud

Computer Skills

<u>Design</u> Functional programming, EA, UML, Design Pattern, MVC, MDA, OO, MVP

Architecture Microservices, Reactive, N-tiers, SOA, SCA, Actor

Cloud Bees, Heroku, App Engine, Amazon S3, GreenCloud

Agile Scrum, Kanban

<u>Web Service</u> Metro, JAX-WS,CXF,JAX-RS,Hessian, Rest, Axis Languages SCALA, Java/JEE/OSGI, C/C++/C#, ADA, COBOL,...

Web PLAY, GWT, Vert.x, WICKET, JSF, PORTLET, JSP, SERVLET, APPLET, HTML

XML, XSL, XSD, JAXP, JAXB, Stax, SAX, DOM, SCALA XML

<u>Database</u> PostgresSQL, MySQL, Oracle, MongoDb <u>Persistence</u> JPA, Hibernate, Toplink, EclipseLink, Slick

Containers Glassfish V3, Tomcat 5/6/7, Equinox, JBOSS AS, Jonas 4, OC4J

<u>Framework</u> Spring, Spring DM, Liferay 4.4, Fuse ESB, Camel, Spring Batch, ElasticSearch

OS UNIX/LINUX, Mac OS, Windows XP, Windows NT, SOLARIS

<u>IDE</u> Netbeans, Eclipse, Idea, JDeveloper 10g

Management IceScrum, Bugzilla, Trello

<u>Build tools</u> Gradle, Maven, Sbt, Javac, Scalac, Ant <u>Version control</u>Git, Subversion, Perforce, CVS, Jazz

Collaboration Trello, Slack, Github, Codex, Wiki, Sharepoint

Training

Project Management Professional, PMP	11.2014
OSGi design pattern: White board & Extender	08.2009
By: Slim Ouertani	
SCA architecture with Newton	01.2009
By: David Savage & Mike Francis	
OSGi, architecture and environment	05.2008
By: Roman Roelofsen	

Publications

Pour le fun : for-comprehension à la sauce Java 8	23.07.2015
Vrais ou Faux Jumeaux ?	25.11.2014
Curryfication Java: methods & fonctions	29.07.2014
Des Lenses en Java ?	30.06.2014
Barboter dans le compilateur Java	02.06.2014
Mon Trampoline avec Java 8	18.04.2014
Démystifier les iteratees avec Java	01.11.2013
Le Trio : Akka, Spring et Scala	16.10.2013
Rest with Scala and Vert.x	18.02.2013
Fun with Scala and Vert.x	11.02.2013
Getting Started with Play 2.1 , Scala 2.10 and Slick 0.11.1	01.11.2012

Please refer to my Linked-in profile for a more complete list of publications since 2008.

News

Java EE et les Anges Gardiens	21.05.2015
MongoDB: la magie des Reactive-Streams avec les Capped Collections	21.05.2015
Publication de l'API Reactive Streams 1.0	07.05.2015
Docker, le dernier clou dans le cercueil des serveurs d'applications Java?	19.03.2015

Languages